Storrs Congregational Church Records.
© 2008 University of Connecticut
Storrs Congregational Church Records.
undated, 1737-1972
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Storrs Congregational Church.
1.5 linear feet.
MSS20060256
The collection contains administrative records and historical documents of the Storrs (Connecticut) Congregational Church.
History
The Second Ecclesiastical Society, creator of the Storrs Congregational Church, was authorized by the Connecticut General Assembly in 1737. Its parent church was the First Congregational Church of Mansfield Center. The first meeting house was built in 1745-1746 on the site of the current church, the present corner of North Eagleville Road and CT Route 195. Situated adjacent to the campus of the University of Connecticut, the church has served the town and the university jointly since the creation of the Storrs Agricultural School in 1881.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the administrative records of the Storrs Congregational Church, including committee minutes and reports, financial records, and church membership information. It also contains pamphlets, periodicals, books, speeches, and original documents related to the church's history and development.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged topically.
Series I: Administrative Records ( undated, 1737-1972 )
Series II: Historical Documents ( undated, 1744-1945 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to various aspects of Connecticut history and the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Storrs Congregational Church 2006-0256.dvd1
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Organizations:
Storrs Congregational Church.
Places:
Storrs (Conn.)
Subjects:
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Administrative Records.; Financial Records.; Minutes.; Speeches.; Bylaws.; Histories.; Deeds.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by the church historian in 2006.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Administrative Records, undated, 1737-1972
  - Abstracts of meetings, 1867-1946 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports
    - 1928 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - 1934 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - 1935 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - 1936 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - 1937 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - 1939 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Board of Trustees minutes, 1926 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Church constitution and bylaws, undated, 1942 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Ecclesiastical Society minutes, 1918-1925 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Standing Committee minutes
    - undated, 1922 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
    - 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
    - 1930 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
    - 1931 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
    - 1932 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
    - 1933 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
    - 1934 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
    - 1935 (Box 2:, Folder 18)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 2:, Folder 19)
    - 1938 (Box 2:, Folder 20)
    - 1939 (Box 2:, Folder 21)
    - 1940 (Box 2:, Folder 22)
  - Church membership
    - undated (Box 2:, Folder 23)
    - undated [1916] (Box 2:, Folder 24)
  - Church schedules, 1913-1918 (Box 2:, Folder 25)
  - Membership list of Second Society, 1742; (negative photostat) (Box 2:, Folder 26)
  - Taxable property in north part of Mansfield, 1737; (negative photostat) (Box 2:, Folder 27)
  - Transfer letters, undated, 1902, 1917-1918 (Box 2:, Folder 28)
  - Financial records
    - 1920, 1927-1931 (Box 2:, Folder 29)
    - 1932-1934 (Box 2:, Folder 30)
    - 1935-1942 (Box 2:, Folder 31)
    - Ledger, 1922-1929 (Box 2:, Folder 32)
  - Real estate documents, 1744-1924 (Box 2:, Folder 33)
  - Real estate documents, 1926-1972 (Box 2:, Folder 34)
- Series II: Historical Documents, undated, 1744-1945
  - Pamphlet, "Connecticut Conference of Congregational and Christian Churches,", undated (Box 3:, Folder 35)
  - Mansfield North parish early history, undated (Box 3:, Folder 36)
  - Handwritten copy of early church records, 1744-1866 (Box 3:, Folder 37)
  - Thanksgiving sermon, 1784 December 2 (Box 3:, Folder 38)
  - Unidentified letters, 1819-1918 (Box 3:, Folder 39)
  - Mansfield burying ground, 1864, 1940 (Box 3:, Folder 40)
  - Connecticut Soldiers' Orphans Home, 1872-1886 (Box 3:, Folder 41)
  - "Manual of the Second Congregational Church..." [2 copies], 1879 (Box 3:, Folder 42)
  - "History of the Congregational Church..." by G. O. Southwick, 1879 (Box 3:, Folder 43)
  - Church history lecture written by Minerva Barrows Whitney, 1898 (Box 3:, Folder 44)
  - "New" Church and Community House, 1921-1926 (Box 3:, Folder 45)
  - Sunday bulletins, 1925-1927 (Box 3:, Folder 46)
  - "Last Service in the Old Storrs Congregational Church...", 1926 (Box 3:, Folder 47)
  - The Connecticut Alumnus, 1935 (Box 3:, Folder 48)
  - "Storrs Congregational Church in Retrospect and Prospect", 1937 (Box 3:, Folder 49)
  - "World War II on the Homefront: Mansfield", 1939-1945 (Box 3:, Folder 50)